I am going to the live hacking event.
Having so many talented hunters there,
I need to do my best and maybe even more.
I found a bug on literally the first day of hacking.
Closed as informative.
I'm not finding anything.
Worst time of my professional career.
Aligned perfectly for a really, really nice bug.
$10,000.
This bug is even better than $13,000.
Total of _ thousand dollars.
I have just learned that I will be going to my first live hacking event.
I just got the email of the invitation to H1702
in Vegas, close to DEFCON.
I have no idea who the customer is.
I have no idea about pretty much nothing yet.
Right now, it's 20th May, 2024.
I'm in Barcelona.
I just got the news.
I am super, super happy.
It was one of my dreams to get to a live hacking event.
And I didn't expect this one as well.
I know I've been plus oned by Justin for the event in January,
and then I kind of expected the invitation.
And I was quite, quite sad I didn't get it.
Now, I knew there was a possibility I will be going to DEFCON,
but the live hacking event I didn't really think a lot about.
But I got the invitation.
I am incredibly, incredibly happy.
And I just, you know, randomly decided to spontaneously record this video.
And I'll probably record the whole journey, the whole...
I don't know. I have no idea yet.
But if you're watching this, it means that I have come up
with a good plan on what to record, and I have recorded it already.
So without further ado, I won't hold you up here for longer.
Enjoy the video.
It is time for the first live hacking event update.
It's 27th June, so there's still three more weeks
until the start of the virtual phase of the event.
But Alex Chapman in the interview gave me a really good tip
to start hacking on the target as soon as we know the customers.
And we do know the customers already.
These are, I hope I can say, if not, I will bleep, TikTok and Epic Games.
And these targets are I've never hacked on before.
So I really, really want to use the time before.
I already have like started a little bit.
I just created Bear Projects and Kaido Projects.
I created my setup and nothing more.
But I really do want to get advantage of starting a little bit earlier
to do some recon, because I do feel some pressure, to be honest,
to perform at this event.
You know, just thinking about having so many talented hunters there
does make me feel that I need to do my best and maybe even more
to do well at the event.
To be honest, I quite like it,
because normally there's not much pressure in bug bounty.
You know, you don't directly compete with other people.
I am my hacking style.
I rarely find duplicates, duplicates.
So I do really like the push to perform at my best.
I'm motivated to do very meticulous nodes.
I already created my my setup with two proxies.
I proxy the traffic. Kaido will be my main proxy.
But in front of Kaido, I use Burp to be able to use Burp browser
because I like DomInvader and to also use some some passive Burp plugins.
I hope the performance will not
will not be too bad with the setup, but we'll see.
Also, I want to try the JS Weasel tool for the event.
It is a tool for working with JavaScript files and it's a commercial tool.
But I asked and they offered to extend my trial
for the period of the whole event.
So a huge thanks for them and a shout out.
You can check out the JS Weasel using the link from the description.
And also, I'm quite puzzled as to what new things should I add to my
to my hacking style, because I recorded two podcasts recently,
one with Alex Chapman, who who spoke about testing desktop applications
and the other one with Joel with TechnoGeek.
And he's a very good mobile app tester.
And one of these targets has a lot of mobile apps,
has like four or five different mobile apps in scope.
The other target has a lot of desktop apps.
And I don't know if I should, you know, invest the time now into learning
about, you know, basically spending time learning something
almost completely new to me,
or I should just stick to what I know and to what I already can do well.
I don't know. I will see.
I will record an update at some point in the future.
So you will see it in a few minutes.
For now, for me at least, it is a mystery of what will happen.
But I am very, very excited.
So we are in between the virtual phase of the live hacking event
and the in-person phase.
I fly to Las Vegas tomorrow.
It is 3rd August.
And the virtual phase was a real rollercoaster for me.
It started quite well, at least I thought it does.
I found a bug on literally the first day of hacking.
And I was happy about it because it was my biggest worry
that I would end up the whole event with with no bugs.
I submitted the bug.
Unfortunately, it was closed as informative,
which I could make an argument against it.
Maybe I will collaborate with somebody because I think there is a potential
that somebody knows better how to show the impact of this.
For now, I can't really be upset about this one.
So I continued hacking.
I submitted another bug.
Unfortunately, it was also closed as informative,
which I wasn't particularly happy about it.
This one, I don't really agree with.
I think the attack scenario that I was able to show should be good enough
to trigger this as a medium and maybe as a low.
But the program decided otherwise can't really do much about it.
So I just kept on hacking, but I was finding no bugs.
And the worst part about it was that I was finding very interesting targets,
interesting functionalities where I was like, oh, one hundred percent.
There are bugs in this functionality.
This is too complex to be secure.
But the problem was that
nothing worked like literally nothing.
I tried worked.
And in some cases, I saw the error message
and the error message basically told me that, you know,
this there has been an attack here, but we fixed it.
Sometimes you just feel that the functionality you're testing
has been vulnerable before, but somebody else got the bounty for it.
And I felt like this here.
And at this point, you also have the Slack channel for all participants
where people can ask for collaborations,
people can ask questions to programs, people can post memes.
And in general, I saw that
first, not a lot of people were finding bugs.
People had problems finding bugs.
So I felt a little bit better.
That is not only me struggling at this point.
The other thing that I noticed was also people
are referencing past life hacking events of the same customers.
And this one was a little bit problematic for me because
in conjunction also with a lot of people asking questions about the targets,
I just called interesting.
So I was like, OK, a lot of hunters are hunting on the same target as I am.
And even worse, they already have the experience from these targets,
from past life hacking events.
And because these targets were part of past hacking events,
they are also quite hardened.
And then they published the leaderboard.
And I saw that at first there weren't many bugs.
But then I saw, you know, people people do find stuff.
And at this point, I started feeling horrible,
like about one and a half week out of the two week virtual phase.
It was the worst time of my professional career,
like I've never felt so bad because of my work, because I felt
like I'm not finding anything.
And one week ago, if you asked me,
I would say I'm almost sure I will end up the event with no valid bugs.
I even planned initially to record the part of this vlog during the event.
But then I was like, if I don't find bugs, there's no point publishing this video.
So I didn't record anything during this phase.
I felt horrible. I didn't want to hack.
I sort of just wanted it to be over.
But then the next week, I just kept on hacking.
I also listened to the podcast, listened to advice from my own podcast,
from one of the recent episodes.
And I did find a really interesting target.
And all of a sudden, everything clicked like my exploit.
All the pieces of the exploit aligned perfectly for a really, really nice bug,
which took me like one and a half days to exploit.
But it is a really nice bug.
I hope I will get the permission to to create a video about this bug.
But for now, I cannot disclose any details.
Unfortunately, it is a duplicate, but because it's a duplicate window,
I will get half of the bounty.
So it doesn't, bounty wise, it doesn't matter if you're the first
or the second person reporting the bug in the in the window.
You still get get your piece of the bounty.
So this is this is the one that the original report is still in the new phase.
So I don't know what will be the risk, but I don't think it will be lower than high.
I think it's either high or critical because I was able to show a lot of impact.
So I'm really, really happy about this one.
And finally, it was on Epic Games.
And as you know, from the from the previous part I recorded,
I spent some time before the event.
But the funny thing is, I spent all the time before the event on TikTok
and then during the event up until the last day, I only hacked on Epic Games.
And I don't know why, to be honest, don't ask me.
I don't know why it just happened to be this way.
But even on the last day of the virtual event,
I got an email from TikTok about a new functionality
in the in the application.
And I noticed that I only got this email to my real account,
to my real Bug Bounty Report Explained account that has real videos, real followers.
I also maybe this is the important bit.
I also actually purchased ads in the past.
And maybe that's why I got the email to this account
and to none of my testing accounts.
And I thought, you know, OK, if they just launched a new product now
and possibly other hunters did not receive an update about this,
I should probably look there.
In like less than one hour, I found a bug.
It is a medium. I reported it as a medium.
It's not a super critical bug, but you might say just a medium.
Mediums during these live hacking events are paid a lot on TikTok.
A medium gives you the range of $2,000 to $9,000.
You can get $9,000 for a medium.
On Epic, it is, I think, $3,000 to $7,000.
So this bug, it was on TikTok.
It went through the pre-triage.
It is in the pending program review state, which means it is not a duplicate.
So I'm really happy about it.
I hope it will be triaged.
I hope TikTok will not come up with some strange
reason why it wouldn't be.
Then I also found another one.
This one, the CVSS said it's high,
in which it actually is.
The problem is it is sort of on the edge of the scope.
I do hope it will be triaged, but it may as well not be.
So these are the three reports that I reported during the virtual phase.
And I'm still waiting for updates on all of them, to be honest.
But then in this between phase,
I also collaborated with another hacker, with Jonathan Baumel.
And the same bug that I reported, I told you, is really nice.
We found another way to get to the same, to achieve the same impact.
Basically, part of the exploit is shared between these two.
But it is a new bug.
And this bug is even better than the one I submitted myself.
So, again, I really hope I will be able to make a video about this.
But this bug we will submit tomorrow once the window reopens.
And I hope that nobody has, because the way these things work
is there is a dupe window that lasts two weeks.
So if many people submit the same bug within these two weeks,
the reward will be split between all of them.
Then there is a pause and then there's another dupe window.
And that another dupe window is when we submit the bug.
But if it turns out that somebody has already reported this bug
in the previous dupe window, we will not be splitting the bounty.
So let's hope this is not the case.
I would be really heartbroken.
But it is what it is.
So I have four reports at the moment that I'm still waiting
for them to be processed.
I'm fairly happy with my performance here.
I hope that the rewards for this will be
what I expect them to be.
Then I will be really, really happy with this life hacking event.
But to be honest, for me, the biggest goal of this life hacking event
is not measured in the number of reports, is not measured
in the amount of bounty I received.
I received it is measured in whether I will get to
receive invitations for future life hacking events,
because the goal for me is
for this event is to show my hacking skills
so that I just get to the life hacking event circle
like keep getting these these invitations to these events.
It will be awesome for me.
It would be really nice to just be able to be part of this.
So I hope that that these bugs will get
processed well, will get good bounties.
Maybe I will even show and tell one of them because Jonathan,
who has been to many life hacking events,
so he knows much more about these than me.
He told me that this bug is a show and tell material.
So maybe we could get to to show this back on the stage in Vegas
in front of everyone.
It would be it would be mind blowing and an awesome opportunity.
So let's let's see what happens.
Probably the next time I talk with you will be after the event from from Vegas.
I hope I will then
get to report on the bounties that I received.
Let's hope they are as high as they can be.
And yeah, see you around.
And the life hacking event H1702 came to an end.
We just finished hacking on TikTok the second day of the in-person phase.
Technically, the event ends tomorrow, but the hacking is done for the moment.
I'm 31st overall and 16th on the TikTok leaderboard.
And I'm really, really happy with this.
Obviously, I will fall a bit down once all the bounties are awarded.
But I'm really, really happy with what happened.
And I'm really happy to be here.
It was incredible to meet so many people in real life
that I've known for years just from Twitter, from YouTube or from different media.
They are amazing people.
I had so much fun and I learned so much.
It's incredible how many different ideas I saw just in one day today.
Because you just talk with people, with people that hack the same assets as I did
and, you know, maybe had different ideas, maybe missed what I did,
maybe came up with some idea that I didn't come up with.
Also, we have show and tell, so some reports
are chosen to be presented on stage to everyone.
And it's also incredible what people are finding here.
So it is a huge, huge success for me.
This also because I learned so much, because I met so many people.
But also I'm happy with the bounties that I got.
So as you know, from before, I had four bugs to be processed.
The first bug, it was sort of split into two different duplicate groups
because for life hacking events, we have dupe windows,
which means it's not only the first report getting paid if there are duplicates,
but within the dupe window, the bounties get split into all the reports.
In my back, it was a chain
and sort of two parts of the chain were rewarded differently.
One part of the chain was a duplicate group with six other reports.
And we got almost $13,000.
So each one of us got about $2,100.
And the other part of this chain was $10,000 split between two reports.
So I got $5,000, which makes a total for this bug $7,000.
Also, I told you I have another bug that we submitted with Jonathan
during the second phase of the event, during the in-person phase.
Unfortunately, this one was a duplicate from a bug submitted in the first phase,
which means we are not splitting the bounty,
which means we are not getting anything for this report.
So this $7,000 is everything for me for Epic Games.
But also I had two reports for TikTok.
One of them was rewarded $10,000 between two reports.
So I got $5,000.
The other one is the only report that is not a duplicate.
It was rewarded $2,000.
So I also got $7,000 from TikTok,
which gives a total of $14,000,
which is an amount I'm really, really happy about.
Obviously, people here are crazy and for them, it might not be
a satisfying amount for me.
I am happy with this.
I know I can only get better.
I hope to participate in these life hacking events more.
So HackerOne and other platforms, you know where to send invites.
And for now, thank you so much for watching the video.
I hope you enjoyed it and see you later.